Uday Lad

Senior Software Engineer

+919657360877 | udaylad8340@gmail.com | Pune, India

Summary

Highly skilled in all tiers of AEM technology stack including AEM, JCR, SLING and OSGi technologies. Experienced in developing components, pages, templates, OSGI bundles, sling services.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, HTL, CSS

Frameworks: OSGi, Sling Model

Developer Tools: AEM, Git, Maven, Jira, Source Tree, Bit-Adobe Lifecycle

Experience

Senior Software Engineer Jan. 2024 – Current

Capgemini Technology Services Pune, India

- Built an AEM component from scratch with Touch UI dialog configurations and responsive design for enhanced usability.
- Developed a Sling Model to handle dynamic data, integrate with JCR, and provide business logic for HTL templates.
- Created JUnit test cases with Mockito, achieving high code coverage by testing edge cases and critical functionality.
- Developed a custom servlet for dynamic report generation in JSON/CSV formats, ensuring accurate data processing.
- Ensured **code quality** and optimized performance through clean coding practices, debugging, and scalability improvements.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to gather requirements and ensure all business-critical functionalities were
 accounted for in the development.

Software Engineer May 2022 - Oct 2023

Capgemini Technology Services Pune, India

- Worked on AEM Migration Project where we migrated, build and validated the content in AEM Local environment as
 well as in Engineering environment and delivered end to end implementation from requirements till production. Used
 MAVEN project structure for building packages, file Vault for importing the code from JCR.
- Generated **content fragments**, models and packages in the local environment and build **jolt specification** to remove the mismatches in the content then validate content with legacy in local environment.
- Set up a **CI/CD pipeline** in 7 steps to push the code in engineering environment with code clean-up.
- Set up the repository then deployed **the content fragments** in engineering environment. Set up and maintained workflows, publishing permissions for the content fragments.
- Generated Cass Endpoint validation and published the content fragments in publish environment.

Education

Shivaji University Kolhapur - Kolhapur, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering

 $2016-2020 \mid \textbf{First Class}$

Languages

- English
- Marathi
- Hindi